they need if if if defunding the police
requires them less bulletproof vests and
guns and tanks and and more into the
schools then yes I I support that yeah
and I like you know um just a way in you
know when we think about the police the
police people a lot of people don't know
that they used to be the slave Patrol
and the slave
Patrol was a um was invented uh so that
they could because after bacon Bacon's
Rebellion where uh you know a a
indentured servant from Britain uh he
went against the colonial powers of the
time and he had blacks and whites
together and uh was he was able to
pretty much burn down um a a particular
County
and they saw that they're like oh these
two people are linking up so now we need
to create some laws um to divide them
and you know and that's essentially when
they created the the white race um and
when you're because like I'm listening
to what you're saying and yeah
everything when it comes to definitions
and terms terms are everything because
once a word is created it goes into the
legal lexicon right so well
yeah yeah I'll finish the point like
yeah so the um so they created
uh the slave Patrol because they then
gave the poor whites and the indentured
servants power over the blacks to
oversee their work so when you look at
the very Genesis of the police they were
they weren't there for protection and
serving they were there to create that
that division with
class yeah and everything's based on Law
and language nowadays and and that's
what people don't understand so if you
if you're if you're in if the police
says you were driving this vehicle or is
this your vehicle blah blah blah where's
your ID where's your how many times did
people cops done this to you this your
ID this right or or how about this this
is this this will this will this will
people understand this can you stand
over here like how is me standing over
here different from where I'm standing
once you give them your ID once you
stand over here like they said like a
good boy go stand over here you are now
under their Authority you lost you lost
so if they kill you they win in court it
doesn't matter you lost you lost your
Authority because they they win they win
people don't know this people don't know
say no I'm fine where I'm standing I
don't need to stand no there if you
don't like where I am you can move and
and you can't give them the authority
you always have to hold your authority
over them you have supreme authority you
know you're you're the people you are we
we the people that's who we are and I've
tested this this is not something I saw
on YouTube this is I've tested this and
I try to figure out why does this cop
always want me to stand over here why
does he want me to sit down right here I
could stand and when you do that when
you sit down on the floor and they
humiliate you and they surround You by
police they're gaining Authority so
whatever they want to do whether they
throw you they want to throw you in jail
then get some money out of you find you
tell you you're
resisting well you know they they
they'll win they'll win because you have
no you lost you lost your Authority it's
a game it's a game and you once you say
yeah what's driving you lost because you
answered that question one two driving
is a legal term meaning you're you're
engaging in Commerce that means you're
you're driving for you're you're
delivering Goods which is not what
you're doing that's what truck drivers
do so so no I wasn't driving I wasn't
driving and no this is not my vehicle
because vehicle or no this is not a
vehicle you know you just can't use
their words it's it's just simple like
you just got to know what the words are
and what they really mean and it's the
same as what what you're you're talking
about Ryan it's it's it's they they they
figure out these laws and they figure
out how to trick you I mean I I I get I
get I question everything I question
everything even the black lives matter I
question I support it even the even the
killing of of of um all the all the you
know the video
well you guys I'm GNA introduce you to
Our Guest are we ready for this are you
ready Ryan I'm ready awesome I'm ready
Take Me to Church Take Me to
Church originally from the Pacific
Northwest Brian Taz Garcia has been a
part of the Los Angeles graffiti scene
for the past 18
years as a self-taught artist Taz rocks
artwork is heavily influenced by various
aspects of West Coast Street culture
including low rider cars hip hop B boy
and Cho
subcultures and prison art you know uh
Beyond tazok skill photorealistic
renderings of the human form he has also
mastered different aspects of custom car
artistry sorry car Artistry such as
airbrushing and pin striping so we would
love
to welcome Mr Taz Rock to the
floor oh yeah what's going on Taz Rock
hey what's up how are you doing hey I'm
doing good doing good just uh woke up uh
half hour 30 40 minutes
ago what just got some coffee had some
coffee at 7
a.m. and where where where are you
located right now I'm in Indonesia
Indonesia wow so it's 7 A.M in in the
morning in the morning yeah wow it's
good though it's fine I get up this time
sometimes earlier it's nice the
weather's great it's perfect it's easy
to get up easy to get up early here
because it's not cold and it's mostly
sunny all the time yeah yeah when it's
cloudy and rainy you're gonna sit inside
and sleep you know I don't czy I can't
do that yeah for sure I was thinking
that you were in I thought you were like
in California somewhere I was like s
o'clock and you waking
up just getting my
coffee cof must had a long day but no
it's it's good thank you so much for
being here so we're gonna get started
and um the first question that I wanted
to ask you
is what is your story so you know begin
at the very beginning um how did you get
into becoming um a world-renowned uh
graffiti artist so you can take me back
as far as uh as you like an infant yeah
um I think I was go there I was just I
was always into art when I was a kid so
um I was always drawing and as far as
you know um I can really remember
playing with toys and
drawing um it wasn't until my mom uh saw
me drawing all the time that she she
told me to um send my uncle pictures um
of my art in prison well I didn't know
he was in prison at the time so she just
said send him pictures he would really
love it I'm like okay he's a really good
artist and then when she told me that he
doesn't get much uh many letters and I'm
like well why why what's wrong I didn't
really understand prison then you know
except for when I get in trouble and get
locked you know that was my prison I
guess if it was that bad then hell yeah
I'll draw I'll draw you some pictures
and send it to
you so so no I I I did that and and next
thing you know he sended me these
amazing drawings like my uncle was um
you know he was an amazing artist and
and both of my parents were were
creative and talented too but so it kind
of just inspired me to um draw more and
um and kind of it wasn't until like I
guess high school when I just right
before high school when I started
getting back into drawing again but I
was exposed to um more graffiti art and
um and my my dad and my uncles they had
classic cars too and there wasn't really
I didn't know how to do murals on cars
really you know I was just out doing
graffiti and then once once my uh
parents and my relatives and Friends saw
me doing
graffiti they were like um can you
airbrush on my shirt or my my pants or
my my my brother's had a mini truck and
so I started doing clothes and cars and
my dad's car eventually and um you know
my my uncles and uh then you know I
started I started making money at that
so that kept me motivated and I L doing
it and there wasn't very many people
doing it at all so um it was pretty I
was staying busy so um but my my real
passion was Citi art and that's when I
was exposed when I I would say like you
know 14 15 but I didn't really get into
it till you know 16 and um and
I I I was like you know I come from from
Oregon so I was in LA and I just saw the
most amazing pieces on walls and to me
that
spoke bigger than painting a car or
t-shirt or a hat or shoes or
something it was um the walls that that
I was just I couldn't even like you know
when I went home I was like that's what
I'm doing like I got to paint walls like
this have to I have to um transition
into larger scale and I had to figure it
out too you know because I I didn't have
anybody show me and I didn't have um
really a mentor I guess I had people
that I was inspired by and you know but
but I guess it was just one of those
things that in nature I I'm I'm very
dedicated at whatever I decide to do you
know no matter what it is you know I
used to BMX BMX freestyled for for
almost a decade and and competing and
traveling doing performances shows and I
really put my mind to that and cuz I
wanted to be on top of the world with
that and
so that that only has so much longevity
and and I know that my body can only
take so much and there's no money really
in it I mean if you look at there's very
few people surviving off extreme sports
you know you have to be way up here to
really survive it that kind of thing and
um but it was you you know it's great
Hobby and I learned a lot from those
things like break dancing and same thing
you can't really you only have so much
of a career it's like a running back in
football you know you can only your
body's only going to take so much before
you know then what you know so um my art
my art I can do it till I you know
forever if I my as long as my hands keep
working you know if not then I use my
feet or my mouth or something whatever
so I I don't I don't really have have a
deadline for or you know expiration for
my art so I I love to do it and and I
can keep doing it forever so um and and
so yeah now I just try to go just like
when I was painting on walls um at home
in my hometowns wherever wherever I
wherever decide to live um back in in
the days when I started there was less
people doing it so you get more of a a
reaction from people now you see it
everywhere you know now it's like just
like La I'm I'm burnt out of LA because
because there's so many amazing artists
so you know you yeah you I'm just
whatever to some people because yeah
they see it all the time they're spoiled
you know people are spoiled in LA with
with the amount of talent but right
right that's why you know I think that
um traveling is has helped me to expose
it more to people that don't get to see
it in front of their faces you know
going to countries in Thailand and and
you know um going to even here and
there's islands all over the place and
you know and people people um it has
more of an impact to me at kind of like
it did when I was younger you
know yeah know I could I could do it
anywhere so
it's yeah well tazra you mentioned that
like when you're sending those you know
those images to your your uncle right um
what got you into that I mean I mean I'm
kind of the same like I'm very artistic
but usually like there's usually um big
influencers that get you to even push
you more farther than what you already
know of your Artistry in general what
were your biggest influences especially
in La there's there's a
lot like how did you build on that like
how did you
breaks I guess the 80s it was it was
different um there wasn't so much I mean
there was a lot in LA and New York and
places like that compared to or you know
in
Oregon but actually you know there's a
um documentary growing up was uh Star
Wars and Star Wars came from New York
and and just it it was a documentary on
the whole graffiti culture and B boying
and everything and and I was just stuck
you know and that was before I was
really exposed to it in LA I mean I was
exposed to it you see you know growing
up even in Oregon there was there was um
dudes doing graffiti I didn't know him
then you know and I was like wow just
walk by it my friends and I would just
be like you know let's let's go do this
[ __ ] you know
sorry I didn't think about cussing I can
cuss I can cuss oh man if I can cuss
it's on
that's GNA happen oh no don't behave
yourself give me that green l i before
you you mentioned I just wanted to just
shout out the people that are in the
room we got kente in the house what's
going on kente we got Anna we have uh
Ivonne um and all the people that are in
here uh just put a number one let us
know that you're in there so we can
shout you out but um you know thank you
guys all for
for tuning in so if you guys can this is
going to be an amazing interview please
hit that share button and hit the like
if you're on YouTube and don't forget
you you guys can um you guys can always
ask questions um in the con in the
comments Anna asked is that surfboard
painted by you behind there it is it is
my uh I did paint it yeah I I snap I
snapped my other one and then everybody
out here has has nice clean white boards
you I don't know CU they're rich or
something so mine was you know yellow
it's kind of they get yellow by the Sun
and worn out and so I was like you know
I'm not going to go out there with a
yellow board I I paint everything I had
I would have paint my bikes paint my
cars so it's like why am I surfing with
a plain board what's wrong with me you
know so I just you know I just tired of
the yellow board so I just put a little
paint job on it but I but I was painting
custom some customers here that wanted
some surbs painted so um painted it and
I was like oh I want to get me a new
board and paint it but I haven't got one
yet I just paint my old one it's all
dinged up and so nothing I didn't spend
a lot of time because it's beat up but
um yeah you don't want to yeah waste my
time on something that's already tore up
for sure so you were saying um you know
walking around you're being immerse in
the 80s with the hip-hop culture and
stuff like that and and you know and how
the 80s really pretty much defined
hip-hop um um and at the time that you
got um immersed with the culture did you
know where where this was all GNA
head no um I didn't um so in the 80s it
was like uh there wasn't there wasn't a
lot of people into hip hop so it was
kind of like a few of us found each
other and it was really easy for for for
someone to recognize uh hip Hopper or B
boy or Citi artist or or you know just
how they looked you how they dressed and
and um I did it because I mean I I I was
into the culture because I loved it like
nobody was doing it and that's what I'm
about like when everybody was
skateboarding I was BMXing you know and
and everybody's dancing like Michael
Jackson I was B boying you know just
like I didn't want to do what everybody
was doing I I just I'm just I I I kind
of just wasn't into like spirited yeah I
just wanted to even if it was um B boy
moves even it was a dance move
everybody's doing windmills I was like I
want to do something else you know I
want to do something I don't want to do
something everybody's doing so um I
would just try to be different with
whatever it was I I try to be unique in
everything I do and that's what right it
just kept you know it's weird how just
here I am now but um I didn't know it
would take me this far I just did it
because I love it that was it and I
didn't do it to please the world I just
did it to please me and that's that's
where I ended up getting um the
satisfaction more satisfaction out of
other people enjoying it and out of
people customers buying my art so that
gave me gave me more incentive to keep
doing it because if I love doing it and
they they love it then you know it's
win-win I I could you know keep doing it
I mean the hip-hop yeah the hip and so
the hip-hop um culture um after you know
uh seeing documentaries and meeting
people in other parts of the US into
hipop you know that's when um you know I
wanted to start um getting people
together in in all aspects B boys
graffiti artists DJs I mean that's how I
grew up I grew up this is hip-hop it's
it's it's the four elements maybe you
got people nowadays that are don't
really maybe younger people that don't
really um think that graffi is a part of
Hip Hop and but it's it all started for
the same reason you know it
all you know there was B boys doing
graffiti so it's like we're the same
people you know and and then you know
then we put our crew together and I've
been in many crews but the first time
that um I was really uh comfortable and
content with the crew was was was my
crew defcom 5 and um that was because
other
Crews kind of like um were scattered
around didn't really know any not not
really like a family you know what I
mean and with just let anybody in the
crew and then who knows what those
people are really dedicated like to me
it was really serious like I this wasn't
like something I got into just for a
hobby or for um for a trend wasn't I
didn't do Trends I wasn't trendy you
know I didn't wear clothes that
everybody wore I didn't you know I was
just sort of an outcast but I didn't
want people to be in it for a trend and
I and I and same with the people my crew
members they were like you know they're
still they're still it's still their
life today you know and it's impacted
them and and even between you never know
you never know when you're that age
who's going to who really takes it
serious who's going to do you know who
really loves it like that because you
know you can fall out of love easy with
with it that's right I just happened to
I just happen to love it you know and
the great thing about Hip Hop was let's
say I got tired of doing graffiti well
you know I can always rap if I wanted to
but I can't you know I can't rap but but
there's that creative El
that that if I really wanted to you know
I know I can't make it happen yeah but
and then I was B boying and and and
graffiti so so then like what do you do
do you do you be boy all day and spend a
couple hours drawing or do I spend a
couple hours be uh bbing and all day
draw kind of like I have to I had to
kind of decide what I wanted to be the
best at for me yeah because you could be
you you know I was like well do I want
to be mediocre at a few bunch of things
or do I want to be the best at one thing
so that's why I decided you know okay I
can't be boy anymore you know all these
young kids are now you know we're we're
doing moves like this that I spent I
spent a month or two working on one move
and then they just like whip it they
just like man I can do that [ __ ] I'm
like God I'm in the wrong field
I can't I I STI dra man these guys and
then just gonna keep getting you know
even in freestyle when I used to BMX
like it was just the young guys would
come up and they would just be able to
do man so much and and I feel now I'm in
a I mean I'm competitive you know so
when I would see B boys I like oh man I
gotta come up with some better things
now you know I got and that's that's how
it works you know that's how it works
you get motivated and and so I think the
graffiti thing now in the
art I still see I still see young guys
come out there and just come out with
this amazing stuff but you know there's
so
much it's it's the the ideas and and
creativity is endless so it's like this
kid could be doing this crazy like 3D
murals with glasses and and all this
stuff and that's really unique and
amazing it's like damn why didn't I why
didn't I think of that you know but
there's so much more that that just you
know the more I paint the more I do
things and and I'll be happy with with
coming up with creative you know ideas
and with the B boying and and physical
uh elements you can't really like you
know it's like it's like mcing or or or
DJing like you you'll never there's
there's an endless amount of of you
could do it forever you know because
there's so many topics you can and so
much music music so yeah I mean and I
had to think about what I really love to
do and what what I can actually survive
off too you know and
so yeah so Taz what is the purpose of
Art and Society to you like with what
you do what is it your I
guess let's start with that because
there's so many so many questions in one
that I'd love to ask you at the same
time are around that so let's start with
that so the purpose what do I um feels
the purpose of art so what
is the purpose of Art in your Society so
even in your culture you know like how
do you how do you bring that into your
art um well I think that um art art can
be funny sometimes
because well what I what I my opinion is
um it's voice right and it's not just a
a voice it is um something that that's
inside here and here that that only I
could see and only I can produce that
nobody else can really I see it in my
head my feelings are just whatever it
is I can project it onto a wall or a
canvas or you know whatever it is I want
to apply you know apply the art to um
and art art is individuality it's
uniqueness it's it's it's that person's
um I guess um personality you know and
when you see when people see paintings
like I don't like I don't like that you
know everybody you not no artist is
gonna please everybody that's why
there's so many artists so art exactly
you could you could see stick figure you
could see a stick figure and people say
I love it that's that it did yeah you
know good you that's awesome because
somebody you made somebody feel good
right or something you know and so my
art is is
for I think it it's to please people who
have the it's like music to me to me my
art is music on a on a wall basically
because um the more people are going to
see it are going to keep wanting to see
more it's it's just like but I don't
always do things that that people
probably like or into you know I used to
paint a lot of women naked all the time
and I had huge fans for that but then I
had to tone it down
so it's nothing you know because we're
all we're all born naked so like people
really tripped on it like yeah my
tattoos and stuff you know people in the
US especially or oh or in in uh the
Middle East they really trip on my
tattoos but it's like well You' never
seen a naked person before before so I
had to kind of you
know but with with with my art it's it's
different because uh a lot of artists do
like to stick to the same genre or Niche
or whatever and I just I like to do all
kinds of things you know I I don't think
to me there's any limit it's just like
like to me the art is like speaking
right it's like speaking or or music so
um I always like to talk about something
different or or you know versus somebody
that just saying the same thing you know
but that's how you get really famous
honestly as an artist the more you do
the same style and you put it in
people's heads that's how you get really
really famous but I don't I'm just not
really me if if I had if I did the same
thing every all the time and looked at
it and and I I have I would have no
purpose to do it that's just money it's
just Fame and money that that that I
would
looking for and it's not really what I'm
into I just wanted you know so I think
everybody has their
own um you know meaning for why they do
art um some people do it for money some
people do because they love it um and
some people just you know who knows have
no reason but um you know I think I
think in ultimately it's it's it's a
voice and it it it's it's um just like
music on a wall I guess yes good good
way to describe it because um it talks
to people you know you can walk by one
mural and not say anything it's like
walking by country music and oh God
Can't Stand country you know but then
you walk by and it's like your favorite
rapper on the wall the the the art
speaking to you like that and then
you're like wow you know I mean there's
there's the artists there's artists that
I I I love seeing their stuff you know
I'm like and I know how it feels on the
other end because I get inspired by Art
and for another artist to to um paint a
mural and like man I can't wait to see
more their work because it's super you
know amazing or dope and yeah and it's
like pushes me to to keep doing my art
you
know so I think it's important Taz Taz
um I don't know if you answered it but I
just want to make sure at influencers
what who did you kind of or if you know
of or
people that you just grew up to
understand their art and kind of mold
yourself in general who are those for
you in that
time and even till now
um I think a lot of the guys I was into
were
um well I grew up um inspired by East
Coast graffiti in the beginning because
that was all I really saw you know off
of TV and um and there was yeah there
was um there was graffiti artists more
into the element of bombing and I was
too and bombing is just doing it illegal
whether it be you're tagging on your
name or doing a a small small letters
like a throw up or big letters or
characters you know whatever level you
wanted to take it illegally what how
however far you um wanted to go you know
and I was inspired by um the big the
colorful and the the detail you know the
the 3D letters was cool was fun and and
I got a rush that's what some people
want they want that adrenaline rush and
and the ones that inspired me were the
ones doing bigger I mean I still was
inspired by guys just bombing getting
their name up everywhere with all
different colors and styles back then I
didn't have one person or anything that
influence me I would say the whole
culture and the whole the whole um
movement inspired me and and um uh I
can't I can't really I can of you know
like graffiti artist like scheme um
scheme had like really Killer letters
and and doing it on subway trains and
and he had this really raw mentality is
like you know I'm you know I'm just you
know I just out there putting my name up
and you it wasn't about like he was out
there trying to make money like get
famous he just was putting his name up
everywhere with you know that that
inspired me um after a while like you
know being exposed to West Coast um more
more West Coast because the West Coast
kind of evolved a little later and and
right to me to me I didn't really look
back after that like I didn't even look
at East Coast Citi because you know I'm
not on the East Coast so it's not it's
not going to influence me as much so
being on the west
coast um you know I was influenced by
guys like slick and hex and and um my
boys down in in San Diego um Saki and
quazar and and these guys were um they
were doing graffiti
like nothing like the East Coast really
I mean maybe some of their stuff but I
mean they and they were taking it to a
photographic portrait level where I was
like and I was I was stunned you know um
I think my my boy my boy saki Who real
close friend of mine um we became
friends after seeing after seeing these
artists work you know you end up
becoming friends with them and knowing
them because this is a small culture you
know right and um and you know and I was
representing the Northwest at the time
because they were they were you know you
had different parts of the US with
different um artists and um everybody
wanted to e meet you know everybody
wanted oh or go paint over here I want
to go paint in this state I want to go
paint in New Mexico or you know and then
you see different artists from different
regions they all have their own little
style but uh I think the the I was
influenced by a lot of the guys in San
Diego too A lot of the artists out there
zodiac and um uh persue and a lot of
these guys were doing super
unique um pieces with uh
style and I'm like okay so how can I how
can I do this now like you know they
just they just showed me a whole another
level and I'm like okay like this is
this on now you know there's no there's
no limit to this after that you know so
I mean I didn't have one
person I could say um that inspired me I
many many artists wow but it was that it
was that super colorful characters
letters
backgrounds that that was what I wanted
to do not just my name I didn't want to
just go do my name I thought that was
too easy too boring for me it wasn't
wasn't you
know my thing I used to um I used to
watch
uh not R my my dad when I was growing
up uh he was the first to bring The
Source magazine to Alberta Canada um he
had the rights to um uh to to sell the
magazine here and I remember flipping
through all of the uh Source magazines
and in The Source magazine they would
have a a like a a page for graffiti and
that's how I learned because I used used
to do I used to dra I used to draw it I
never tagged I never got the you know I
was too young to be going out there
spray painting and and whatnot but I was
always enamored by how they would make
all these you know like it's just these
masterpieces you know it's taking
letters and arrows and doing all this
stuff and making it look like it like
some people were so good that they made
their art look like Voltron or some sort
of like you know machine right just the
way that you look at it yeah what would
you because everybody has a
style um you know what would you say
what verbs describe your
style oh you know that's that's a tough
thing for me um I think it's really
important to have style but um I think
that I I don't
know I don't know how to describe my
style because I try so many different
things all the time then I feel like I
change up my style like I it almost
feels like every time I I approach a
wall I'm starting like for the first
time like I I try to come up with a
unique way to approach it um try to do
something I haven't done
before um but as far as what I do I do
try to commit to um a certain technique
that I guess can be um you know noticed
as a style while I'm painting I mean
it's
um uh um I guess mostly I I've been
doing a lot of really I don't know how
describing words like I don't have a I
don't have a um dictionary of art wordss
so I'm just like I I I did a I do a lot
of um really soft um photographic kind
of um
work um I guess um yeah guess maybe a
better maybe a better way of um asking
this would be like you know what would
your like how would people describe it
themselves like how would they know that
this is this is Taz
rocks I don't know I don't know because
I I don't see it on that so I ask people
sometimes I'm like like that's like I
could tell I could recognize your style
I could tell you did that I'm like oh
really like how because I I'm not sure
how um I mean I guess it could be the
way I paint u a lot of my portraits
um uh uh I I guess because sometimes I
do really realistic and then sometimes I
I kind of characterize it a little bit
you know so right um but it could be it
could be the women I paint because I
painted so many portraits of women in my
time that they see a girl painted that
it can probably recognize it it's me I'm
I'm thinking but most of the time I I
change it up you know I I got paint from
uh you know I like doing skulls and I
like doing people I like doing I like
doing women um but sometimes I get bored
of it so I try other stuff you know try
a new thing I painted a peacock not too
long ago I'm just like all right my
friend said I want a peacock peacock huh
okay so uh but I don't know how my St
style doesn't always fit into that you
know because right because see the the
the thing about a lot of artists how
they create this style over and over and
they're able to sell that style over and
over but
me I I'm doing different jobs like uh
somebody hire me for this somebody hire
me for that somebody will say do
whatever you want just do me something
cool and then I'm like wow that's free
reign you know I can just come up with
something I've always wanted to paint
you know maybe it could be a car because
I like painting cars you know um right
yeah
so there's many well that's one of the
girls that you did behind you hey the
girl in the the purple face behind you
that's one of them right this one yeah
right there that one that's one of your
girls yeah that's beautiful yeah I
painted I painted that in Thailand um
and this is kind of the thing that I I
I'm more into right right now you know
is is is um women and and it's kind of
the um the Day of the Dead sort of style
um sort of mixed my version of of uh
well it's Cho art because you know I'm
Cho and
um right and I try to um
share my culture where I come from to
other parts of the world so this that
was in Thailand so um you know it was
something that you know I could go to
Thailand and paint something having to
do with Thailand but that doesn't that
doesn't um you know reflect who I am so
I paint something that's me you know
like the one over here is in is in
Germany that's in Germany with my boy
Tunes I couldn't fit the whole thing on
one paper but it's a two production it
goes says tunes and Taz and that's
another one of my Inspirations is my is
tunes and
um um we are in Germany and we we did
low rers car we painted low rers in our
names and and and and script lettering
because we're both we both come from the
same culture you know he he's not he's
not Cho but we come from the same
culture it's not there's know like low
riding low riding in custom cars isn't
just Cho culture it's black white asian
everything but but um yeah so um him and
I we we did a production and um we we're
bringing our culture to a whole another
country you know that's what I'm into
more you know it's like it's like I
could do this all over the us
but and I I just don't get anything out
of it anymore as much as I used to you
know and I get stuck in the the US and I
get stuck doing all these corporate jobs
and these corporate jobs don't really
reflect who I am that's why this these
paint drawings are up there because
those are my own designs those aren't
those aren't something that I was G
given to and reproduced kind of like the
Suns of Anarchy right yeah like that was
right right right so I just wanted to
shout out all the people like uh holy
moly a lot of people watching we got 14
people in the house uh we got David
Garcia proud of nephew uh Taz Rock hey B
that's my uncle hey
Uncle he's always he's so kind Romero uh
uh I don't know how
too
yeah um showing some cousin from
Mercedes Texas
beautiful we got Andre my Texas Family
she says that's important because the
whole time I'm thinking I would love to
learn the process of graffiti Arc it
seems very hard and you only get one
chance I don't know if we get one chance
you only got one life you only got one
life
exactly I knew you're gonna say
something I know you too
well so Anna says shared both on my
walls thank you Anna and
um Cable says Taz rock is one of my
favorite artists I know him from way
back he's super talented Big Ups bro uh
cable oh cable oh cable yeah what's up
cable one of the dopest MC's out in
Portland that's for sure nice welcome
Trent Barry says uh T de um has a
signature style it's very dope the women
he paints are so realistic yeah for sure
what's up Trent that's my old school
homie he's got building line huh I'm
sorry oh oh no that's okay sorry R yeah
rigor says I love I lived there for half
Year beautiful and the last comment oh
we got one more of your friends uh T
timot Tim Tim he
says
Timmy and we got Daddy in the house
daddy says love following your career
such an amazing artist beautiful you got
all kinds of love right
now I'm glad people showing up like
remember I never know I thought it was
just gonna be us three I'm cool
that he's
horrible he thinks like everybody forgot
about him no no my gosh no we just want
say to all of you guys if you're
watching on YouTube you um feel free
we're inventing the world's first living
documentary where we're going to be
documenting the lives of you know black
and Latino cultures around the world
using new technology um that will allow
people to add to the narrative that H
you know and this has never been done
because once a documentary is shot it's
done but um you know with our technology
at hustle Zone we'll be able to add
commentary after the fact and build the
world's first living documentary where
everyone could be immersed in a new
experience watching the same story over
time so if you guys
can the link is in the description
please click on there donate two five 10
you know 100,000 million dollars you
know do do us a favor you know send us
send us money your way and if you are
watching YouTube you guys have the
opportunity to send us a Super Chat uh
send us a Super Chat and just comment
that you did and we'll shout your name
out um uh we'll shout your name out and
and and give you some props uh and then
the last thing is um don't forget folks
uh go to our YouTube channel And
subscribe and hit the notification Bell
so you know because we're gonna have
tons of great people on this podcast and
hopefully Taz Rock will come back
another uh another interview or you'll
kick back with us uh again but you guys
want to subscribe because we're going to
have a lot of people
as great as Taz rock on here so um
anyway go ahead
Monica yeah
so my question I always want to ask you
um what is the Legacy what is a legacy
you want to leave behind in your work
what is it that you want to teach what
is it that you want to show what is it
that you want to educate in your
work um what I that's that's um
well I would like to have my work um on
walls for a long time where this is kind
of one of the things that that um why I
traveled outside the US
because in LA and lots of places in the
US where where you know I've been and
live um graffiti seems um it doesn't
seem like it lasts forever you know
canvas can last forever because it's
hung up on a wall uh
right and in a home it's
protected um and I love that like I love
painting canvases but I think I want to
leave a a legacy for one the first first
thing would be to have my mural stand
the test of time and until they're
because because with with spray can
you're using um you know heavy duty
materials inside the can right and and
they last years years you know um I
would love to see my art and and other
people's art Stay instead of getting
painted over and another mural because
that's how it used to be us to just we
do a mural and then it could it could be
gone in a month you know and people ask
me where can I see some of your murals
I'm like well [ __ ] not a lot of them are
are up they've gone painting it over or
somebody else did a mural there or
that's right you know or they a new
business opened up you know so they
painted over right yeah and and it I
would love to see mural's stand and for
Generations so so people can look at see
you know for for kids can see later on
maybe that'll Inspire them you know when
they get older you know it could be
faded it could be chipped but it's still
there you know and even past that even
even after I'm gone you know I would
love to have my art because because my
physical can be gone but you know
hopefully a piece of me that came from
me can be still you know on the wall um
that and to U just
Inspire um kids you know Inspire anybody
it could be an adult I mean you don't
have you could start painting now at you
know 50 who knows you could start
there's no there's no expiration there's
no um deadline really until you know as
long as long as I I I inspire people to
do it and and that it is possible like
like every time I I have a chance to
paint with some kids or some guys I I
show them something you know I want them
like they're like oh how did you do that
and I'll explain the whole I'll sit
there talking forever because normally I
won't talk a lot I'm just you know very
chill and but if you start to talk to me
about my art and and wanted to know
something how I did this and how I
achieved you know uh this projection how
do I get it the scale it on the wall or
whatever and I love to show people
different ways you know and how I get
the small lines and to me that to me
that's more important like my my art is
not it it's it's something that a gift
that was given to me which we all have
this my my um my idea and that we all
have a gift we all have whether it be um
could be anything right you know but but
it's to we have to get to me I have to
give back I have to I have to show
somebody my crap so that then they can
learn and then they can it just keeps
keeps the art form going and inspires
because the whole reason hip-hop started
you know was to get um people out of
gangs same with low writing you know and
like like these
cultures create were created something
because people were tired of going to
jail tired of um fighting you know
there's more productive ways to to do
create and and my life what uh and
people people's lives um they don't get
exposed to so many things and this is
why I have to travel the world I there's
enough people in the US there's enough
people in the US doing doing amazing art
I I I think that the rest of the world
needs more people in small villages and
in countries where they don't where they
get internet but how do they know that's
real you don't know what's real unless
it's in front of you you know and if I
can produce murals and paintings that
are right in front of them they can
actually touch on the wall and see it
with their own eyes and see somebody do
it then that to me is is um keeps me
going and that's that's what I want to
leave it doesn't it's it doesn't have to
be you know that I mean when I get
people come up to me and just say they
inspired me and this and that like
that's it you know I feel like I'm
finished I feel like I did my job but
but why quit now you know why why stop
doing art now I I still love it it still
has the same effect on on the world and
I'm just going to keep doing it as much
as people can love looking at it
yeah you know I I think um I was just
going to say because you said that hip
hop started with um you know just you
know as a subculture to get you know
people out of gangs and and get them
preoccupied with something else um and
Hip Hop in itself being you know a mode
of expression um do you what about some
of there are some when it comes to
Graffiti um in particular
you know it's an art but there are some
people that paint over the graffiti um
you know and there are people they're
going to jail you know for vandalizing
and you know putting their artwork on
sub on on sub trins and
um and um you know on walls Etc so what
is your opinion on you know like is
graffiti an art is it also vandalism is
there a gray line uh between then I know
that now that you are you know you
obviously made this a career so you have
your corporate clients and whatnot but
what about those young kids that are you
know tagging the side of a you know a a
train station or whatever what's what's
your opinion on that well I wouldn't say
go go I wouldn't say go do it illegally
but um but there's so much graffiti out
nowadays and so many people becoming
successful successful from legal
graffiti and illegal graffiti which is
funny because you have people that that
say oh that's vandalism or oh painted on
my wall it's vandalism if it was done
without permission that's just plain and
simple if it was done without
permission or on some guy's building it
could be it could be this amazing
portrait but it was some guy's building
that didn't nobody said I they could do
that's my building I pay for this
building it's mine my business business
why is somebody think they can paint my
building it's mine right nobody should
and I I learned that later on like you
know it's selfish of me to go out and
paint people's walls but it's only paint
right it's just paint like you're and
people take it like they they take it
they get mad like you know people get
killed they in I've read I've read
articles where kids were killed for
painting on and chased down by by a a
random like the Ahmad
Aubrey um like just hunted down by by by
vigilante by standard people you know
because they were painting on a wall I
mean it's it's so harmless he's not
hurting you're not really physically
hurting somebody but it is their
property they don't have the right
doesn't give anybody right to take
anyone's life or hurt anybody it's it's
not it's it was you know unless it
there's no unless it's just there's no
there's no reason for anybody to take
anybody's like no nobody has like that's
just [ __ ] but sorry for saying that
cool okay so the reason the reason why
I'm saying this is because what what's
funny now now you have a whole huge uh
following of of artists right like for
example look at bky okay bky is doing
illegal graffiti everywhere and he's and
he's loved it in fact people cut out the
wall because it has value they'll
they'll they'll take the whatever
jackhammers and they'll cut out pieces
of the wall because they're worth
millions right wow that that that's what
I need to do so yeah draw something so I
could cut it out but he's doing it
illegal but if somebody else that wasn't
bky did it illegal there will get
painted over people would be mad you
know but it just depends on who who's
who's viewing it like you know um I I
don't really I think people you people
in the hip-hop culture still want to
keep it real you know keeping it real
um but keeping it real can go wrong
because um it's just something they do
for like you know some people can't make
a living off of doing it you can't make
a well thany I can't say you can't but
it's hard to make a living off of
something IL legal other
than uh you know like drugs and so you
know things like that but but graffiti
he you can become famous for doing it
illegal sometimes so um I don't say go
do it I don't say I promote it um but
it's only paint it's just paint you know
it could be painted over um but I think
the only difference between the two is
if you have permission I've painted on
walls and people come up to me are you
you're doing that illegal and blah blah
I was like I'm getting paid from the
owner right or it doesn't matter if I'm
getting paid or not the owner gave me
permission so so it's only vandalism or
illegal graffiti when it's done without
per permission that's the only
difference like people say oh that's
legal now I mean I was doing legal
graffiti when I first started like
people saw me doing it oh can you paint
my bike shop I was like that that become
then it's not vandalism then it's just
it's just art or it's it's it's legal
graffiti because it's all based on law
really you know it's just if they have
permission and it's illegal if it's
vandalism vandalism is based on on a
legal term I guess and not just that
it's based on someone's opinion and if
it's their building and you paint it
I've seen guys like this crazy uh
painted with this muralist back back in
um I would say the early 90s and this
guy was painting with brush portraits
this this is this is crazy because he
was painting it I could have been on a
7-Eleven on a 7-Eleven right 24 hours
they were open while he's painting this
mural on the side but nobody cuz he's
painting a portrait of somebody people
thought he was commissioned so he's just
painting this portrait nobody said
anything I'm not going to tell you he
was white or anything but he was light
skinned I'm just kidding no but he was
he was painting a portrait so if it was
somebody young a younger kid or um you
know uh maybe maybe me or something
painting my
name or painting a picture or something
it wasn't a portrait people would
probably people probably come up to me
and call the cops call the cops nobody
called the cops nobody called the cops
on him because he was painting a
portrait it didn't seem like vandalism
so that was based on somebody's
perspective but if you talk to 7-Eleven
we didn't ask this guy to do you know
it's vandalism right so it's based on
where you do it whose perspective you
know who would who it affects yeah so uh
okay so we have um we got some more
comments here uh Sean says I always
enjoy great art yes and so that you guys
know behind me on my great
screen oh yeah look at that this is Taz
Rock's uh I I'm chilling at his miral
right now so damn that's still there no
see that's another one that's that's not
there anymore we cut it out oh that's
not there anymore holy moly yeah that
that was in melro it says City of Angels
City of Angels City of Angels it's
beautiful it's it's all inspiring but um
you know so yeah that's that's example
of great art uh we have um Tim he
says Timmy Mr Tim otus fo says I can
attest to this Taz is a Tru Testament to
giving back my brother is such a cool
and humble Soul thank you for being so
dope dope friend or being a dope friend
Taz so thanks
Tim man he's the one that um he's took
the photo that you're using for my
profile oh he took the photo oh yeah
he's the photographer like he he he did
um some other stuff for me we work on
things together but you should one day
like that made me I guess it's a
museum oh sorry I was gonna say with my
bad I was gonna say with all the work
you've done you're GNA have to one day
do like a like I don't know if you'd say
Museum but I mean like a walkth through
with all the pictures you've taken
because
obviously there's some stuff that is not
there anymore right but put everything
together to really like celebrate your
work because you've done amazing amazing
art thanks you know you know what I'm
going I'll be going to that just so you
know you know what sucks sometimes is
like I don't have pictures of a lot of
things I've done in my past and and or
I'll take them with a crappy phone or or
low quality and like print like you know
and I try to print it or something and
it's like low quality it's like I got to
stop using my phone for stuff you know
and get a real camera yeah but yeah I
just like sometimes I just do stuff I'm
I'll go by get a picture someday and I
just never do or um you
know but I got to start doing that write
I write a note to that right
now awesome right now okay so um there
seems to be a delay on the podcast so if
you guys are noticing delay um it's just
uh technical difficulties but um you
know uh we are heading up to we're g to
be done within uh 101 15 minutes so um
please hit a number one in the comments
are you still there knock knock knock
Hala can you hear me are are we uh are
are we still in the house and and let us
know what you guys think about the the
broadcast um U by putting your comments
in the comment section just let us know
that you're here uh and um yeah and
we're going to finalize um you know this
interview but I think Monica has a
question for you my
friend what is the most liberating thing
about being
Nomad um what liberates you well you
know what it's funny but sometimes I
feel like I'm more free um outside the
US than than the US says we are free
right Freedom yeah I understand yeah um
yeah I think that that
um it it's it's kind of hard to explain
but because different places are are
every country is different you know but
the reason why I I've chosen why just
right now just to be in Indonesia one
for one is because I can't really leave
anywhere but um I can't leave anywhere
actually because of the lockdown stuff
and the borders and whatever so um to me
it's it's like I can go pretty much
anywhere and do whatever I want and um
without like
um you know there's certain restrictions
and certain laws that aren aren't so so
um hard here in a lot of countries you
know it's funny to say just for example
just like riding around on my motorbike
here you know just like you don't need a
you don't always need a helmet or or
license or anything like that you know
and you're not always looking out for
police even when I'm painting a mural
I'm not to worry about the police
getting called on me a lot of a lot of
me being outside has a lot to do with um
the system how it's ran in the US um
it's also it's also um you know it it's
I feel like um I can I can also um teach
a lot more people that are they don't
have the access to um to artists because
a lot of artists come to you know travel
a lot of artists travel right but right
I like to go meet artists from
everywhere that that aren't exposed to
my style of art or my my techniques and
things like that so um I have it feels
really good to to just be able to um
meet new people and from other other
parts of the world and just like it's
cool because most of the countries speak
English you know and and so it's not
really really a hard thing to to get
around so I I don't know I
just I I I guess I would just say it's a
lot I feel a lot more free you know it's
a weird thing to say third world
countries and things like that I mean
I'm not doing anything crazy enough
where that that I I'm be in trouble you
know and and in fact it's lot easier to
paint walls out here you don't get the
police call on you I could just go up to
mostly any wall out here and just paint
it and pretty much nobody's gonna say
anything you know um so that's really
one of the big things and that's what
like when if some of my friends ever
come out here that are artists I'm like
that's a good wall right there it's like
we could just paint it we could probably
just paint it and maybe just knock on
the door and say hey can we paint your
wall same thing as this one here in
Thailand I just went and asked some of
the locals do you know the owner and
then they went in they say yeah yeah and
then I like hey I'm going to paint this
wall and they're like okay okay it's
just like this was in the US man no it's
different yeah it's not gonna work that
way and then the city's gonna ask for
permits do you have a permit if it's
like for a sign or business you know
it's going to be regul regulated and
it's like no man I'm just over all these
regulations and CRA do you things oh
sorry I didn't mean to interrupt there
seems to be a delay do you do you think
um with you being a nomad right now um
there's this big thing called pandemic
and people are locked in their homes um
and um and there there are travel
restrictions and travel banss um you
know has has those travel bands uh
affected you and what's your um you know
and what's your your your view on the
Travel
bands
um well that hasn't affected me I mean
well I I guess the travel bands have the
travel bands yeah there's there's um
there's no traveling right now which is
fine because I don't really want to go
anywhere right now I cool where I'm at I
I I can't tell you how much better it is
out here than the US and how many
Americans I've met out here that say the
same thing um that
after all the things that are going on
how the US is handling
stuff this this not really a huge
problem out here as far as um pandemic
wise and lock lockdowns and things it's
everything's to see seems pretty normal
it's just like the ones that are really
afraid are going to stay in but then
they're probably not you know they're
probably like well [ __ ] I want a party
you know we're going to Bali I want a
party surf you know but but people
people here it's just it's different
where it's not so crazy lockdown and
there's not so much I mean people you
know there's a big thing with the masks
in certain stores but yeah um and then
there's some signs that say you should
wear
it but I don't think it's I haven't been
in the US but from my friends tell me
it's just like not cool and um and I I I
I think I'd rather be here it it's the
the traveling is fine if I can just stay
here in fact it it's pretty good because
they put a um I don't have to um renew
my Visa my my um right yeah you know
it's it's We have basically any warer
has a free stay here um so okay so
because you can't leave normally people
leave come back and Renu renew the Visa
stay right correct or they get an
extension but um right now it's it's
like there's no there's probably out
everywhere I've traveled this probably
the only place that I I would be if if I
knew this was all gonna happen ahead of
time I'd say okay I'm coming to Bali I'm
gonna get away from the real
problems so so Chaz um before we head to
round
two um we yes we have a round two y'all
it's called lightning Round And if you
guys are familiar with hustle Zone we
always got a lightning round uh
but before we go into round two and then
we'll before we H into r two we're going
to read your comments uh but uh what are
your thoughts on you know black lives
matter movement right now uh what's
happening because I'm sure you growing
up and being immersed in part of the
hip-hop culture um you know you probably
you've probably seen you know you've
probably been around and you seen uh
people that were in you know gang life
Etc um and having to deal with the
police you know what what is your your
opinion about black lives matter and and
most importantly pre police brutality
and if you've had any incidents um or
seen any incidents um while you were
coming
up um okay yeah definitely um this could
be a really long long subject but I'm
gonna try to keep it keep it short
because I um growing up um in Oregon you
know um I'm Brown so the police always
had a problem with that my brother and I
we've always dealt with with police
harassment on profiling my brother's
been my brother's been beat up by police
um there's there's there's no I mean I
don't I people may not hate people may
hate me for saying things like um all
police are bad all police are wrong
that's my opinion okay because um I know
firsthand this is not a vid it's not
from a video I saw like this is this
could get really heated with me if
somebody's talking to me and they say oh
the police don't do that oh this doesn't
happen yeah when when it's happened all
my life since I was able to ride a bike
since I was riding my bike at 14 15 16
always getting pulled over by the police
on my bike then I get an Impala right
because I like classic cars and then
there many of my friends know they've
all been there with me cops pulling me
over and pulling guns out on me you know
so there's no it's not it's this is this
is not new to black and brown people
because it's been happening for years
I'm thankful I'm alive and the cop has
never shot me and and believe me I've
had the guns pointed at me and pulled
and like they they can just pull a
trigger right now I could just be dead
you know they throw me on the ground
there's many techniques they use I I I I
I I do blame myself for not educating
myself and and one thing I'm just going
to try to make this really short and
quick but the problem was me because I
and and also the systems because they
don't teach you how to how to defend
yourself in court how to defend yourself
against the police as far as what to do
what to say but there's a lot of things
people are doing wrong is why the police
think they well the police get they get
authority over you people people lose
their rights without knowing they lost
their rights that's why the police get
away with all this stuff like you have
to study um the right things to say do
and and how to act and all these
statutes codes and and and and um these
these laws they're they're they're laws
most of them they're not even all laws
sometimes they're just codes you know
they're just they're just infractions
and things like this but but the police
are trying to create Revenue so the more
you get dig yourself in a hole the more
money they can possibly
make and I've learned this I've learned
this and every time I started
researching everything after I'm like I
was over it I'm like I need to just
figure this out because if if if I'm
getting bullied every day at school
eventually I'm gonna learn to fight okay
so this is a fight against a system that
people need to educate themselves and
fight with their mind not with physical
you have to protest you you have to
stand up for black lives matter matter
right because that's what's happening
black people are getting killed and when
people say well we all matter of course
we all matter that's that's that's just
that's D hello we all matter every human
life matters but what's happening is
police they kill they do kill black
people and that's what they
statistically and what's happening the
most because we all have cameras we
didn't have cameras when I when the
police were were tackling me you see
what I'm saying or my brother they we
didn't have cameras somebody wasn't
there filming
you know and I've seen them in La lately
and then they they've tried to get me
for for resisting arrest you know you
can't resist arrest if you're not under
arrest and that's the trick you are
under arrest once they stop you and they
turn the lights on so everything you do
and say can be used against you so my
thing to everybody if you ever encounter
a police and don't say anything you
don't have to say anybody anything to
anybody no human can take that will from
you you can shut your mouth you don't
have say a damn thing because if you do
that and if you open your mouth and you
start to piss a cop off that's when they
they they get out of hand they're done
even in the protest it's just like you
know the protest that needs to happen
that that needs to happen it's been
needing to happen and I think is the my
my opinion is because everybody's been
cooped up and and and everybody's just
like created this rage and everybody's
online and all these police videos of
beating up black people and killing them
and and and and just random people
killing a black kid jogging down the
street like this nobody should die and
no man has the right to take another
man's life period he's just a man in a
uniform you know that wins he's a man
that wins in court so you have to know
the system know how to defend yourself
in court know what to say how to people
just have to study these things because
it will save their life and and it's
protected me I've tested the system been
to jail been pulled over had my car to
all kinds of things and I've tested the
system it's not after after studying it
I have to research to see okay does this
work and it does it does but you but
people it's a lot to learn but the basic
and simple fundamentals is to just know
that they are they are just man they are
just man like us and we're all created
equal so no man is above another so yeah
there needs to be protests on the
streets for the Liv that the police have
killed
because we have we have a court system
whether whether whether somebody that
says well he was well he was a drug
addict and he was high on PCP while he
was cops arrested him so that's okay
right no it's not okay no man has the
right to take another man's life at
least give that guy every man has the
right to a fair trial when I say man I
mean human yeah in general but every
every man has the right to Affair trial
how the system works so they don't have
the right to take anybody's life but
they just they're just um they they're
trained they're they're trained to to
use Force imagine if you got a new toy
and you couldn't use it or you you
learned Kung Fu and you couldn't you
couldn't do do anything with it right
and the Chance comes oh I'm gonna use it
right like when like this is all police
they're all they're all made created
like built to to be this way and and
they know what they're doing they know
oh well there's a nice cop out there I I
can't even get into it but but you if
another cop sees that happening how has
that caught a good cop if another cop
standing there watching another man
knowing knowing okay th this is not
right every man knows what's right and
wrong and they know we have the human
instinct to to do what's right to do
what's wrong this why we don't need this
why we shouldn't have authority like
that because we all have common sense we
all know it it's not right to steal we
all know it's not right to hurt and kill
but education systems poverty we're not
all equal because we don't we have poor
and we got rich we got a guy next door
with this huge flat screen TV and then
we got this kid over here with with a
nothing you know with a cheap phone and
and it's just like that's why you know
there's crime and and just we're all
separated we're all separated e
economically and and and through color
for some ridiculous reason color is a is
a is a is a a hate act you know I don't
get that I I never got it all my friends
white black as every every everything um
I don't I don't I you know even when my
I hear people you know saying racist
stuff growing up I've had people races
against me all the time I didn't take I
didn't get mad you know but it but but
after a while you you do got to stand up
you do you do have to you know I I I I'm
totally for being on the streets and you
know not destroying things but but you
have to show that that you ha you have
the supreme authority you you they
they're they're servants and they they
are they're civil servants and but but
people lose their Authority when they
gave it up by talking by handing over
pieces of paper giving them any kind of
anything I teach this and I and I study
this and anybody anybody who has any
questions can call me and say hey if I'm
pulled over by a cop I'll tell you
exactly what to do you do nothing you
don't give them nothing you don't say
nothing and they have nothing take you
to court what are they gonna do find you
for what for for for nothing because you
didn't give them anything that's all it
is it's a bun it's a it's a business so
I could go on and on but I'm not I'm
just going to say that's the basics like
I I'm I support it and
hopefully if makes a difference because
you know there comes a time when when
police
abuse their their Authority and and
thing is thing is they're supposed to
protect the people and and you know and
and they're supposed to go by the system
how it works um legally through the
courts and and they're they're not
they're not a judge they're not a jury
and so they have no right to to to take
that matter into their own hands and
they're not lawyers so they they they
cannot you they cannot they cannot tell
you the law they cannot tell you what to
do and what is the law because they are
not lawyers for one so I mean it could
go I go on and on about it because this
is I spent I spent like five years just
studying this on my own because I'm
tired of it I'm tired of police
harassing
me I'm just tired
and course and I mean a lot of people
are yeah yeah protest is a is a start
but the the the the number one thing is
to educate yourself just to study you
know get books go into go the documents
are all out there all the laws are out
there all the way to defend yourself is
out there just gotta know it Taz I
remember when I would uh get together
with my dad because he go to many
different protests even for the
aboriginals and uh my dad I mean he came
as an immigrant to Canada and he would
have he would take me with him and he'd
have this
like okay if something happens you this
is all you got to do like don't do our
parents yeah our parents were like that
as well you know or or just people in
our communi so very understanding what
you're saying like if you don't know by
all means you guys educate yourself for
sure you do you do you gotta and
everybody should carry something like
that on them you know it's it's it's um
it's not just constitutional rights it's
human rights it's natural we're we're
we're born with god-given rights that
that are inalienable that nobody can
take away and and the people people are
afraid once the cops approach them and
then they they start to talk and then
they get nervous and like well why you
nervous so you know so it it it's it's a
game that they're playing and you just
got to know how to how to play them at
their own game same as court all comes
down to court everything that comes down
to court because they're creating money
and
revenue and and as long as you can
understand on that you can win has um
sorry for stopping there but what about
relocating the funds defunding the
police from defunding the police so from
the police to the communities what are
your thoughts well I I I think that
there's there's some details to
defunding a meaning defunding there's a
meaning there's a meaning to everything
especially even when you say
driving people people don't understand
when you say driving
that that's just when I get in my car
and I go somewhere no it's not it's a
it's a word used in law it's it's law so
if you're talking about defunding the
police I don't know that because I
haven't researched it because it doesn't
and you hear different things from
different people oh defund the police
that means there's no police there's
going to be chaos in the street I'm
pretty sure that's not what it means I'm
pretty positive that's not what it means
how that's that's ridiculous because
there are people that are lot of people
are poor there's crime of course there's
going to be somebody there but what's
happening I think that the're they're
getting funded with so much military
equipment have you ever seen a police in
La I don't know if they have them like
that where you're from but they look
like military they have vest machine
guns like they're ready for war they're
ready for war war against who crazy
terrorists where are the terrorists like
what did they're ready they're fighting
their own people and they're getting
money that's our money we're giving them
to fight us
oh let me let me just give my neighbor
that hates me or something a gun oh you
hate me here let me can I buy you a gun
I mean if you want to say that that
defunding the police is to take away
some of those rights yeah if that's what
it is but if you got to think about it
that perspective because it's it's it's
people think oh you you're gonna have
wow people running around the streets
that's crazy no and we're got to buy
guns now no no it's if you take away the
guns from everybody even the police
then you don't have to worry about
people killing but
also people need to be educated
education system yeah you should take
money because PE police get paid
probably too much and and teachers get
probably paid crap and I know they do I
don't need to say probably they do they
don't get paid enough and so they don't
if if you don't get paid enough how much
incentive is that for you to do a good
job your your job if you're just getting
this much money why should I even try
you know why am I going to give my 100%
but but money is incentive but also the
education system I think personally
needs to change because there's a lot of
history that everybody's learning right
now why is everybody learning all this
new history oh my God I didn't know that
that was that I just learned this yeah
because our system doesn't teach us
those things they don't teach you how to
do taxes they don't teach you about the
IRS they don't teach you about about if
you go to my son was in School I've gone
to my son's schools and I went off on
the dean the dean is like is like the um
what is it in prison the the um the you
know the like the principal yeah not the
sorry like more higher yeah you know in
prison I don't know I don't know why I
can't I haven't been in prison in a
while
um no so so um but listen um real quick
uh I went to my son's school and and the
the the principal was was running it
like a prison and they had the police in
there and I'm like what do you do here
officer you just give kids fines and
arrest them for something they had but
and then I told to the principal like or
the dean I like what do you do like you
don't teach these kids how to defend
themselves against the police and how to
how when they get stopped and the cop
asks them something you don't teach them
these things it's like what is this a
prison like what do you do is you is
this a business too is this school a
business where you're making money off
these kids' parents because they got a
little weed in their pocket or
something you know and and and the
problem is is these schools don't have
the right education like we don't know
the right history we just got the
history that they teach you in the book
you know I mean you can learn math
science and things like this but but
there's a lot more fundamentals of life
that we run into After High School that
they don't teach you so yeah if they
need if if if defunding of police
requires them less bulletproof vests and
guns and tanks and and more into the
schools then yes I I support that yeah
and I like you know um just to weigh in
you know when we think about the police
the
police people a lot of people don't know
that they used to be the slave Patrol
and the slave
Patrol was a um was invented uh so that
they could because after bacon uh
Bacon's Rebellion where uh you know uh
uh indentured servant from Britain uh he
went against the colonial powers of the
time and he had blacks and whites
together and uh was he was able to
pretty much burn down um a a particular
County and they saw that they're like oh
these two people are linking up so now
we need to create some laws um to divide
them and you know and that's essentially
when they created the the white race um
and when you're because like I'm
listening to what you're saying and yeah
everything when it comes to definitions
and terms terms are everything because
once a word is created it goes into the
legal lexicon right so well that's
yeah yeah I'll finish the point like
yeah so the um so created uh the slave
Patrol because they then gave the poor
whites and the indentured servants power
over the blacks to oversee their work so
when you look at the very Genesis of the
police they were they weren't there for
protection and serving they were there
to create that that division with
class yeah and everything's based on Law
and language nowadays and and that's
what people don't understand so you if
you're if you're in if the police says
you were driving this vehicle or is this
your vehicle blah blah blah where's your
ID where's your how many times have
people cops done this to you this your
ID this right or or how about this this
is this this will this will this will
people understand this can you stand
over here like how is me standing over
here different from where I'm standing
once you give them your ID once you
stand over here like they said like a
good boy
go stand over here you are now under
their Authority you lost you lost so if
they kill you they win in court it
doesn't matter you lost you lost your
Authority because they they win they win
people don't know this people don't know
say no I'm fine where I'm standing I
don't need to stand no there if you
don't like where I am you can move and
and you can't give them the authority
you always have to hold your authority
over them you have supreme authority you
know you're you're the people you are we
We the People well that's who we are and
I've tested this this is not something I
saw on YouTube this is I've tested this
and iy to figure out why does this cop
always want me to stand over here why
does he want me to sit down right here I
could stand and when you do that when
you sit down on the floor and they
humiliate you and they surround You by
police they're gaining Authority so
whatever they want to do whether they
throw you they want to throw you in jail
then get some money out of you find you
tell you you're
resisting well you know they they
they'll win they'll win because you have
no you lost you lost your Authority it's
a game it's a game and you once you say
yeah what's driving you lost because you
answer that question one two driving is
a legal term meaning you're you're
engaging in Commerce that means you're
you're driving for you're you're
delivering Goods which is not what
you're doing that's what truck drivers
do so so no I wasn't driving I wasn't
driving and no this is not my vehicle
because vehicle or no this is not a
vehicle you know you just can't use
their words it's it's just simple like
you just got to know what the words are
and what they really mean and it's the
same as what you're you're talking about
right it's it's it's they they they
figure out these laws and they figure
out how to trick you I mean I I I get I
get I question everything I question
everything even the black lives matter I
question I support it even the even the
killing of of of um all the all the you
know the video
e
e e